RYAN PEART

Data Engineer with experience in data analytics. Reputable for analyzing issues, forming strong client relationships, and providing solutions to best resolve the problem. Proficient in ETL development, pipeline creation, and data visualization using SQL, Python, and Power BI.

(425) 691-6095

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-peart/

EXPERIENCE

DATA ENGINEER SENIOR ANALYST | MAR. 2022 - PRESENT

Accenture | New York, NY

- Developed and optimized ETL workflows to ensure the timely and accurate delivery of data to downstream systems.
- Applied expertise in data platform engineering to design and implement data solutions that improve the efficiency and accuracy of data processing.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify client needs, develop project plans, and deliver high-quality solutions on time and within budget.
- Utilized business analytics tools and techniques to perform data analysis and develop insights for clients in Insurance, Life Sciences, Retail, and Financial industries.
- Leverage industry best practices and emerging technologies to continually enhance project outcomes and drive client success.
- Fostering mentorship programs amongst employees at Accenture and establishing connections to prestigious Universities in the Northeast to engage and introduce students and recent graduates to Accenture culture.

DATABASE ANALYST | OCT. 2019 - FEB. 2022

Minerva Knowledge Management, LLC. | Seattle, WA

- Improved Product Development, Quality, and Sustaining Processes by implementing optimized, structured, and traceable systems and processes.
- Utilized client-facing skills to represent Minerva within the client's environment and drive discussions with senior personnel regarding client's user requirements, methodologies, risk mitigation, and updates for enhancement of applications.
- Built automated business workflows using APIs to integrate application data into other third-party platforms, such as Salesforce, SharePoint, and more.
- Instructed training sessions for hundreds of attendees to introduce and familiarize the use of QuickBase and PowerApps DBMS applications.

PROJECTS

STOCK INVESTMENT ANALYSIS TOOL

- Designed stock analysis tool to help identify undervalued stocks worth investing.
- Developed Python script to gather data, analyze, and rank selected stocks based on certain valuation methods, including P/E Ratio, PEG, ROIC, Graham Number, and more.

BUDGET TRACKING APPLICATION

- Developing an application to help plan and analyze spending habits.
- Using Python and APIs to connect to financial banks and ingest credit card transactions.
- Adding a Goals feature to ensure spending is under budget and feeds towards personal rewards.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

SEATTLE, WA

B.S. Informatics | Class of 2019

- Informatics Senior Capstone Project:
 - Product: teaching tool for online information privacy
- Identified the problem, gathered user requirements, and provided a working solution all within six month period
- 100% satisfaction approval rating from users, teachers, and peers
- Dean's List: 2016-2019

SKILLS

SQL:	****	Excellent
Excel:	****	Excellent
Power BI:	***	Great
Power Apps:	***	Great
Tableau:	***	Great
Python:	****	Great
R:	****	Great
Java:	***	Solid
JavaScript:	***	Solid
HTML:	***	Solid
CSS:	***	Solid

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Snowflake SnowPro Core Certification
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Certification
- Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals Certification
- QuickBase Expert Builder Certification
- ARA Chairman Scholarship 2014
- INFO 201 Best Data Analysis Project
- 2015 NWAC Baseball Champions